mybusiness.com.au 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy | My Business

**Privacy Policy**

Momentum Media Group Pty Ltd (ABN 24 610 789 369) (‘we’, ‘us’, ‘our’) is the publisher of this website, its associated printed magazines (if any), its associated events and conferences, and electronic media products including but not limited to newsletters, Podcasts and forums.

The Privacy Act binds us and protects your personal information. The Australian Privacy Principles (APP) within the Privacy Act directs how we collect, use, hold and disclose your personal information. 

Where applicable, the EU General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) governs the way we collect, use, hold, process and disclose your personal information. Under the GDPR, we are a data controller and processor. We make decisions on how and why your personal information is processed.

This Privacy Policy covers the following websites, events and conferences, associated applications and social media platforms:-

  * Accountants Daily
  * Adviser Innovation
  * Defence Connect 
  * Fintech Business
  * Independent Financial Advisers 
  * Investor Daily
  * Lawyers Weekly
  * Mortgage Business
  * Momentum Connect
  * Space Connect
  * My Business 
  * Nestegg
  * Real Estate Business
  * Risk Adviser
  * Smart Property Investment
  * SME Adviser
  * SMSF Adviser
  * The Adviser 
  * Wellness Daily
  * Which Investment Property

**What personal information do we collect, hold and process**

When you purchase and/or subscribe to our products or services, we collect information that is necessary to provide you with those products or services. For example, we may ask for information such as your name, demographic information, postal address, email address consent records. 

Our platform may also collect other information such as your location information when you visit any of our website, browsing history, browser cookies, device identification, Internet Protocol (IP) or social media platforms.

We may also process information about you from your use of our services including visiting any of our websites, subscription to our newsletters and participation in our survey. We may also process your views and opinions that you or other users choose to send to us, or publicly post about us on social media platforms or our websites, including on any forums we host.

We may also produce analytics associated with your personal information and other information. 

**How do we collect personal information?**

We collect personal information directly from you. We may do this electronically through our product website when you purchase and/or subscribe to any of our products or download any of our report, or our clients’ reports. We may also do this when you register for newsletters, download regular updates from us as well as entering into competitions, events and conferences we organise.

Sometimes we collect personal information about you from other people or a third party such as social media network sites. This may also include publicly available sources or information you have made publicly available, or lawfully from our partnering companies, business partners or stakeholders.

We may also create user information about you, such as records of your interactions with us on our websites, your participation in our surveys, and details of your purchase history for internal administrative purposes and analysis. We may also combine data you have provided to us with data obtained from third parties such as social networks and other data collection entities.

 **How do we hold personal information**

We hold most of the personal information electronically in secure databases and/or files. We may hold personal information physically because the law requires us to do so. We use a range of procedures and security measure to protect your personal information we hold.

 **Why do we collect, hold, process and use your personal information**

We collect, hold, process, use and disclose your personal information so we can provide you with products and services you have requested. We may also use your personal information to keep you up to date with our products and help you to manage these products and services.

We may also collect, hold, process and use your personal information for any of the following reasons: -

  * communicate with you; 
  * analyse engagement with our readers, subscribers, clients, and customers;  
  * observe users’ engagement and purchase activity across our websites and brands; 
  * conduct surveys; 
  * ensure the security of our systems; 
  * conduct investigations where necessary; 
  * compliance with applicable law; 
  * improving our products and services.

**Use or disclosure of personal information for marketing**

We may use or process your personal information to contact you via email, or telephone, or mobile phone about our products and services offerings that may be of interest you.

We will not do this if you do not consent for us to do so.

If you decide you do not want to receive marketing offers from us, you may

  * unsubscribe from our newsletters at any time; or
  * contact us on the details listed at ‘Contact us’.

**Tracking technologies and online behaviour targeting and retargeting**

We may process and use your user information by placing or reading cookies and similar technologies on our website(s). Certain tracking technologies enable us to assign a unique identifier to you, and relate information about your use of our websites, services and products as well as other information about you. This may include your user information for the purposes of learning more about you so we can provide you with relevant content and advertising.

We also use these technologies to 

  * analyse trends;
  * deliver services and product to you; 
  * collect and store information such as user settings; 
  * analyse anonymous browser identifiers and video viewing history; 
  * supplement our server logs and other methods of traffic and response measurement; 
  * gather demographic information about our reader, subscriber, client and customer base; 
  * improve our understanding of traffic on our websites and social network;
  * analyse audience behaviour;
  * responses to promotional campaigns.

**Lawfully process your personal information.**

We may process your user information where: 

  * you have given us your consent; 
  * it is necessary for a contract between you and us; 
  * it is required by applicable law;
  * it is necessary to protect the vital interests of any individual; 
  * we have a valid and legitimate interest in processing your personal information

**When and who do we disclose your personal information to**

We may share your personal information with a range of service providers. The purpose of the disclosure is the provision of products and services. These providers may include mailing houses for distribution of publications and specialist providers for electronic email distribution.

We may also disclose your personal information to 

  * legal and regulatory authorities as required by relevant law; 
  * any party as necessary in connection with legal proceedings; 
  * parties who process user information on our behalf;
  * any purchaser of our business and brands;
  * any third party providers of advertising, plugins or content used on our websites.

**When do we disclose personal information overseas**

We may disclose your personal information to recipients based outside of Australia. They are service providers who assist us in the delivery of products and/or services you have purchased or subscribed to.

This may include service providers who assist in distribution of electronic communication to you.

For applicable GDPR personal information and other information, we may transfer your Personal information to recipients in other countries. Where we transfer user information from the European Economic Area (“EEA”) to a recipient outside the EEA that is not in an adequate jurisdiction.  We do so on the basis of standard contractual clauses between the other parties and us. 

**Data Security**

We have appropriate technical and organisational security measures in place designed to protect your user information against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure, unauthorised access, and other unlawful or unauthorised forms of processing, in accordance with relevant law.

However, as the transmission of information via the internet is not and cannot be completely secure, while we have reasonable measures in place to protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information when transmitted to us using the internet. Any such transmission is at your own risk. You are responsible for ensuring that any information you send to us is sent securely.

 **Data Accuracy**

We take every reasonable step to ensure that any of your information that we collect, hold, process and use is accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date. We also take all reasonable step, where any of your user information that we process and use that you inform us of is inaccurate is corrected, or erased or rectified in compliance with APP and/or GDPR.

 **Data minimisation**

We take every reasonable step to ensure that your user information that we process and use is limited to the user information reasonably necessary in connection with the purposes set out in this Policy or as required to provide you with the products and services you requested. 

**Data Retention**

We will retain any of your information indefinitely until you instruct us to erase them.

 **Control of your information**

You can directly take steps to unsubscribe from any of our newsletters, product and services.

If GDPR is applicable to you, you may have certain rights including: 

  * not to provide your personal information to us; 
  * accessing to your personal information; 
  * to request rectification of inaccuracies;  
  * to request the erasure, or restriction of processing, of your personal information; 
  * to object to the processing of your personal information; 
  * to have your personal information transferred to another controller; 
  * to withdraw consent;  
  * to lodge complaints with supervisory authorities. 

We may require proof of or need to verify your identity before we can give effect to these rights.

 **Access and Correction of personal information**

You can request access to your personal information. You can also request us to correct your information. Please contact us on the details listed at ‘Contact us’.

 **Concerns and complaints**

If you have any concerns about how we handle your personal information or if you would like to submit a complaint, please contact us on the details listed at ‘Contact us’.

If you are not satisfied with our response, you may contact the Australian Information Commissioner. You can contact Commissioner Office at  
GPO Box 5218  
Sydney NSW 2001  
Phone: 1 300 363 992  
Website: www.oaic.gov.au

Contact Us  
Phone: 02 9992 3300  
Fax: 02 9922 6311  
Mailing: PO Box 6311. North Sydney. NSW 2059.  
Email: [publisher@MomentumMedia.com.au](mailto:publisher@MomentumMedia.com.au)

You may contact our Privacy Officer by writing to PO Box 6311. North Sydney. NSW 2059.
